newseum.org 2018-05-23

# Privacy Policy | Newseum

The Newseum is aware of the privacy concerns of online visitors and is committed to protecting your privacy.

#### Personal Information Collected on this Website

We are a nonprofit organization that does not sell advertising, and we do not collect personal information about you, unless you provide us that information voluntarily online. Examples of when we collect personal information include when a visitor purchases an item from the Newseum’s online store or elects to add his or her name to one of our mailing lists. In no case will we sell, rent, license or provide that information to any third party unless required to do so by judicial, legal or other government proceedings.

If you receive communications from us, it is because we believe you are interested in the events and activities of the Newseum. If you prefer not to receive promotional e-mail messages or other communications from us, please select the unsubscribe option on the email and your email address removed from that mailing list.

#### Use of Cookies and Scripts

Freedom Forum Institute and Newseum websites collect aggregated and anonymous site-visitation statistics using cookies and scripts. We do this to improve content and services offered to site visitors and to ensure that our users have the best possible Internet experience on our site. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information. When someone visits our site, a cookie is placed on the visitor’s computer (if the visitor accepts cookies). If the user has visited the site previously, the cookie is read. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that.

**What Our Websites Collect Through Cookies and Scripts:**

  * The total number of visitors to our website
  * The pages visited
  * How long visitors remained on the site
  * The domain name and IP address from which visitors are connecting
  * Shopping cart information for visitors using our online store
  * Type and version of Web browser, such as Internet Explorer or Netscape

We use server- and browser-side scripting to collect information that helps us optimize and tailor our website to the capabilities of individuals’ browsers. In addition to types of browsers, the information collected through these scripts includes available plug-ins, platforms (Windows, Macintosh, etc.), connection speeds and monitor resolutions. We store this information in an aggregate format only, so that we can better tailor our site for our visitors.

#### Note to Parents and Children

The Newseum welcomes children to learn more about the importance of a free and fair press and freedoms guaranteed all Americans through the First Amendment. We are particularly respectful of the privacy of our young users. We encourage parents to monitor their children’s use of the Internet and to help us protect their privacy by instructing them never to provide personal information on this Website or any of our Services without permission. We will never attempt to extract unnecessary information from our users, regardless of age. Consistent with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"), we will never knowingly request personally identifying information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If a child under the age of 13 wishes to sign up for a user account on our Website, he or she must first obtain parental approval and provide a parent’s email address for confirmation. As soon as we receive email confirmation from the parent’s email address approving the child’s user account, we will activate the account. The consenting parent or guardian may monitor the collected information, revoke permission to use previously collected personal information, or delete his or her child’s account by contacting us at [webmaster@newseum.org](mailto:webmaster@newseum.org). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with such information without consent, we will use our best efforts to remove such information from our files. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that a child under 13 has provided such information to us, he or she should contact us at [webmaster@newseum.org](mailto:webmaster@newseum.org) so that we may deactivate the user account and remove all personally identifying information from our Website and servers.

#### Hyperlinks to Other Sites

We may provide links to other websites not owned, controlled or affiliated with our website, but we are not responsible for the privacy practices or material provided by other sites.

#### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update this privacy statement. We recommend that visitors revisit this page periodically to learn of any changes to our policy and practices.

#### Contact Us About Our Privacy Policy

#### Image Permissions

All Content is Protected by Copyright Laws.

Images, text, software, documentation, electronic text and image files, audio and video clips, and other materials are protected by copyright laws and may be covered by other restrictions, as well. The Newseum retains all rights, including copyright, in data, image, text, and any other information contained in these files. Copyrights and other proprietary rights in the material on this website may also subsist in individuals and entities other than, and in addition to, the Newseum. The Newseum expressly prohibits the copying of any protected materials on this website, except for the purposes of fair use as defined in the copyright laws.

#### Share
